<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on phireheavyindustries</title>
    <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on phireheavyindustries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>PT</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-09-09</title>
      <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/blog/2020-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/blog/2020-09-09/</guid>
      <description>The android app is mostly done, i&amp;rsquo;ve added a few screenshots and some information about the logic for this app and a couple of notes on the development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020-08-30</title>
      <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/blog/2020-08-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/blog/2020-08-30/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new update to the to do app that is being developed for Android and Firebase. I&amp;rsquo;ve also added a new projet to the web development section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forged</title>
      <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/apps/forged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/apps/forged/</guid>
      <description>Most to-do and objetive tracking apps are either too cumbersome or too simple, both of which put me off from using them. I tend to revert to an excel file where i can name a task, prioritize it, write a few notes, set a date and routinely update a percentage to indicate how much of a certain task is done. My challenge is to build an app with a free backend so i can use it anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled MessageBoard API</title>
      <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/apps/untitled-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/apps/untitled-api/</guid>
      <description>This is a project abandoned by a client but i have decided to finish it myself. It is a small social network oriented to allow users to comment on various topics or products. The objetive was to have several discussions rooms where one supervisor or admin would launch a topic of discussion and then he/she would create teams based on gender, age and location. The users would then be allowed to voice their opinions on the matter at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quizbreaker</title>
      <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/games/quizbreaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/games/quizbreaker/</guid>
      <description>I love the idea of making some sort of digital game that could be played by a group of people in person. This is a very early concept for a trivia game where one user would build a quiz with a number of questions. Then they would invite other players to play. One user would ask the questions and the others would play, either individually or on teams. Since this would be a multiplayer game there are a number of technologies that would have to implemented, along with a number of decisions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenbreaker</title>
      <link>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/games/zenbreaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.phireheavyindustries.com/games/zenbreaker/</guid>
      <description>Was a simple experiment in Unity to better understand the mechanics of what it takes to build a simple game, including launching and publishing to the Play Store. It has since been abandoned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>